mary.com 2005-02-07

# Mary.com Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

We treat your personal information in the manner in which we wish other sites to treat our own personal information: securely, with respect for us as individuals and with good judgment. Our Privacy Policy is reviewed with each new employee at their orientation and annually with all employees, so that each of us understands what is expected of them: to respect and safeguard the personal information of our members and visitors. Our Privacy Policy, along with additional explanation, is available [here]. We appreciate that you have chosen to place your trust in us. Privacy Policy Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) COPPA regulates the online collection of personal information from children under 13: This site does not comply with COPPA Mary.com is intended for use by adults only and anyone under the age of 18 is prohibited from accessing this web site. Parents should monitor children's use of the internet and teach children about the potential dangers when participating in forums, chat rooms, etc. Guidance for parents and children is available at <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/index.html>.

#### IP (Internet Protocol) Address

Every computer on the internet has an IP address: that's how our servers know where to send the pages you request with your browser. Your Internet Service Provider (ISP) assigns to you either a permanent IP address or, more often, a random IP address each time you sign on to the internet. The IP address assigned to your computer reveals no personal information about users. We use IP addresses to analyze internet traffic and diagnose communications problems

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data that our server sends to your browser when you come to our site. Your browser transmits the cookie back to our server as part of its normal operation. Cookies are not "plug-ins," contain no program code and they cannot access your hard drive. They cannot be used to spread viruses, etc. Cookies are identified with the web site which sent them to your browser and cannot be accessed by other web sites. Mary.com uses cookies to recognize you as a visitor or member of our service. This allows us to supply your browser with the personalized web pages that are integral to our service.

#### Single-pixel GIF's

At Mary.com, we do not use "single pixel .gif's". Most of us recognize ".gif" as a type picture file, similar to .jpg and others. A "Single-Pixel GIF" is essentially a picture contained in a web page, however, it is too small to be seen. Each time you view a web page which includes a .gif, your browser requests that one-pixel file from a web server. Those requests are used to track your movement through each individual page within a web site.

#### Your Profile

You are invited to complete an individual profile whenever you wish. You may include as much or as little about yourself in your profile as you wish and you may add to, remove, or change the information in your profile at any time. If you are uncomfortable providing private information or simply do not wish to take the time, you can enjoy using Mary.com without a profile at all. (It just makes matching you less precise.) How do we use the information in your profile? We say "your profile" because the information is yours to control and you determine if and when to share your profile with others. You may decide to make your profile freely available to all members of Mary.com. If you keep your profile private, you can later share with your partner during any chat session: there is a button on the chat window to display your profile. (Note that your partner must be willing to share their profile with you in order for you to add them to your Friends List.)

#### Friends List

When a person is on your Friends List, it's easy to start a chat or set up a date for later. To protect your privacy, we allow you to control when your name is placed on another member's Friends List. No one can add you to their Friends List unless you choose to display your profile to them during a chat.

#### Information Sharing

We will never share, trade or sell your contact information or any other information which you provide to us.

#### Introducing Your Friends to Mary.com

In order to set up a friend for a blind date, you must supply that person's email address. We use that email to send your friend an invitation for a blind date and then delete that email address from our system. We will never utilize any email address submitted on our "Set Up a Blind for a Friend" for promotional activities or provide these email address to others.

#### Third-Party Advertising

At present, Mary.com does not sell banner, pop-up or other advertising on our web site.

#### Email and Correspondence

We retain all correspondence sent to us, electronic or otherwise. If you send us correspondence or others send us correspondence, or others members send us comments about your activities on this site, these are place into a file made available only to authorized personnel.

#### Actions by Law Enforcement

We will not voluntarily disclose your personal information to any law enforcement agency. The laws of the United States spell out circumstances under which we may be required to disclose information to law enforcement agencies, the procedures they must follow when making a request, and how the information provided may be used. We may be precluded from notifying the person or persons whose information is the subject of an information request. We specifically disclaim any responsibility to notify you in the event of a lawful information request, without regard to whether such notification is legally permitted. In the event we may become subject to the legal jurisdiction of other countries, we will comply with lawful requests in accordance with applicable laws.

#### Please note the following exceptions to our general policy above:

Where we may become aware, by whatever means, of actions or circumstances that in our sole judgment presents or may present a danger to a visitor or member of this site or any other person or property, we reserve the right to notify and provide information to any law enforcement agency which we may deem appropriate in our sole discression, without prior or subsequent notification. We reserve the right to notify and provide information to any appropriate law enforcement agency, without prior or subsequent notification, in order to protect and defend the rights or property of Mary.com, its owner, and employees.

#### Changes in Our Privacy Policy

Prior to implementing any changes in our Privacy Policy, we will make these changes available to members and visitors.

#### Questions?

Your questions and comments are always welcome at Mary.com. Please address them to us at [privacy@mary.com](mailto:privacy@mary.com).
